rawstory.com 2019-12-28

# Raw Story’s privacy policy – Raw Story

The Raw Story and its parent company Raw Story Media, as well as its advertisers, are deeply committed to protecting Internet users’ privacy. Below is information outlining our continued support for the responsible management of consumer information. This policy governs all Raw Story properties, including but not limited to Raw Story, PoliticsObserved.com, Blue Lemur and RawPrint.com.

Consumer Information

During the process of delivering an ad to you, Raw Story and its advertisers do not collect any personally identifiable information about you such as name, address, phone number, or e-mail address. However, Raw Story and its advertisers do obtain some types of non-personally identifiable information such as the Internet Service Provider you use to connect to the Internet, your browser type, your country, the type of computer operating system you use (Macintosh or Windows, for example). The information collected by The Raw Story and its advertisers is used for the purpose of targeting ads and measuring ad effectiveness on behalf of our advertisers.

In some cases, you may voluntarily provide personal information in response to a specific ad (this ad may ask you to fill out a survey or provide your zip code). If this does occur, Raw Story or its advertisers may collect this information on behalf of an advertiser. This information is used by an advertiser to respond to your request. In addition, Raw Story or its advertisers may combine this information with other users’ information and review it in an aggregate form to understand the type of individuals who view a specific type of ad or visit a particular kind of website.

Data Collection

The Raw Story or its advertisers, as well as most sites on the Internet, may use "cookies" to enhance your experience on the web. Raw Story or its advertisers cannot use these cookies to personally identify you in any way. 

What are cookies and why do we use them?

A cookie is a unique number that is provided to you the first time Raw Story or its advertisers serves you an ad. This unique number, which is stored in a cookie file on your computer, helps our advertisers tailor for you. This cookie can help Raw Story or its advertisers ensure that we don’t serve you the same ad multiple times, and help our advertisers understand what you like and don’t like about their offerings so that they can cater better to your needs the next time you are interested in their products or services. While we believe that cookies enhance your Internet experience by limiting the number of times you see the same ad and delivering more relevant content to you, they are not required for The Raw Story or its advertisers to deliver you an ad.

If you do not want the benefit of cookies, there is a simple procedure to manually delete your cookies. Please consult your web browser’s Help documentation for more information.

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

The Raw Story works with third party advertising agencies who serve ads to this site. Each of these agencies have their own privacy policies. If you have any additional questions about The Raw Story’s dedication to consumer privacy, please [click here](mailto:editor@rawstory.com) to send us a message.
